CURRICULUM VITAE





Amman, Jordan



+962-777414338 +962-64799000 Ext.2641



nsaadi@philadelphia.edu.jo dr.najlaasaadi@yahoo.com



http://www.philadelphia.edu.jo/acade mics/nsaadi/



https://drnajlaa.github.io/

Dr. Najlaa Saadi Ismael

SUMMARY

I am Assistant Professor of Pharmacology; I have PhD in Pharmacology; I have more than fifteen years of academic extensive research and teaching experience at the College of Medicine and Faculty of Pharmacy using up-todate instructional technology experience. Furthermore, I worked Director of Research and Development, Planning and *Informatics* department and as Committee member of the Curriculum Development in the College of Medicine and Coordinator of Pharmacology, Toxicology and Therapeutics in the Faculty of Pharmacy. I have a versed in formulating research goals, researching methods and testing parameters, analyzing data, generating detailed reports. My main research interests include research related to various Clinical Pharmacological field.

Languages:

• English: Full Professional proficiency.

• Arabic: Native Proficiency

Degrees (Qualifications):

1. PhD in Pharmacology, College of Medicine, University of Mosul, Mosul, Iraq.

2. M. Sc in Pharmacology, College of Medicine, University of Mosul, Mosul, Iraq.

3. B. Sc. (Dental Surgery), College of Dentistry, University of Mosul, Mosul, Iraq.

Educational Information:

Ph.D. Thesis

Comparative Effects of Telmisartan versus Valsartan on Serum Leptin and Homeostatic Model Assessment of Insulin Resistance in Hypertensive Patients with Type 2 Diabetes Mellitus.

Ms.C. Thesis

Monitoring of Some Liver Function Tests During Ranitidine and Omeprazole Therapy.

Teaching Experience:

- 1. Teaching of the Pharmacology 1, Pharmacology 2 & Pharmacology 3 in Faculty of Pharmacy, University of Philadelphia, Amman, Jordan. (2015 until now).
- 2. Teaching of the Pharmacology for 3rd year students in the College of Medicine, University of Mosul, Mosul, Iraq. (10years).
- 3. Teaching of the practical Pharmacology (laboratory) for 3rd year students in the College of Medicine, University of Mosul, Mosul, Iraq.

Past Jobs (Occupation):

- 1. Coordinator of Pharmacology, Toxicology and Therapeutics in the Faculty of Pharmacy, University of Philadelphia, Amman, Jordan. (2016- 2018).
- 2. Assistant Professor, in the Faculty of Pharmacy, University of Philadelphia, Amman, Jordan. (2015 until now).
- 3. Lecturer in Department of Pharmacology, College of Medicine, University of Mosul, Mosul, Iraq. (10 years).
- 4. Director of Research and Development, Planning and Informatics department in the College of Medicine, University of Mosul, Mosul, Iraq. (3 years).

Experiences, Certificates and Professional Courses:

- 1. Participation in the Session of Laboratory Teaching Styles, organized by the Center of Developing Teaching Methodology & University Training for the University of Mosul Lecturers.
- 2. Participation in the Teaching Methodology Session, organized by the Center of Developing Teaching Methodology & University Training for the Scientific Promotion for the University of Mosul Lecturers.
- 3. Participation in the Session Organized by the Computer & Internet Center for the Efficiency of the Computer for Graduate Students for the University of Mosul.
- 4. Participation in the session organized by UNICEF about the breastfeeding in Baghdad.
- 5. Participation in the training workshop : Ethical Issues for research , Philadelphia University, Amman/ Jordan
- 6. Participation in the PhD Applicant workshop (Queens university Belfast 2018)
- 7. Participation in the Google form and Google drive workshop , Philadelphia University, Amman/ Jordan
- 8. Participation in many medical and pharmaceutical conferences and Symposiums.
- 9. Ability of analyzing the data by Statistical Package for Social Sciences (SPSS) for medical research.
- 10. Teaching with use up-to-date instructional technology.

Professional & Scientific Committees

- 1. Committee member of Quality Assurance, Faculty of Pharmacy, University of Philadelphia, Amman, Jordan
- 2. Committee member of Academic Advising in the Faculty of Pharmacy, University of Philadelphia, Amman, Jordan
- 3. Member of the Community Committee at the Faculty of Pharmacy, University of Philadelphia, Amman, Jordan
- 4. Committee member of the exams in the College of Medicine, University of Mosul, Mosul, Iraq.
- 5. Committee member of the Curriculum Development for Department of Pharmacology in the College of Medicine, University of Mosul, Mosul, Iraq.
- 6. Committee Member of the Collection to Curriculums for all Departments of College of Medicine in the University of Mosul, Mosul, Iraq.

RESEARCHES

Published Research

- 1. Perinatal depression. Prevalence, suicidal idea, and associated factors. (Journal of Pharmaceutical Sciences and research, volume: 12 No.1, 2020).
 - Journal URL: http://www.jpsr.pharmainfo.in/Documents/Volumes/vol12issue01/jpsr12012021.pdf
- 2. Book Chapter 12: Quality Control and Testing Evaluation of Pharmaceutical Aerosols. (*Drug Delivery systems-* 1st *Edition, Published date:* 1st *November* 2019).
 - Journal URL: https://doi.org/10.1016/B978-0-12-814487-9.00012-0
- 3. Efficacy of Follitropin-A (Gonal-F) versus Follitropin-B (Puregon) for Controlled Ovarian Stimulation in Women Undergoing IVF. (International Journal of Pharmaceutical Quality Assurance, volume: 10, No.04, 2019).
 - Journal URL: http://ijpqa.com/index.php/IJPQA/article/view/649
- 4. The Effect of Using Combined Oral Ethinyl Estradiol and Levonorgestrel in the Resolution of Menstrual Pattern Disorder and Functional Ovarian Cyst. (Annals College of Medicine Mosul Volume: 41, No.2, 2019).
 - Journal URL: https://mmed.mosuljournals.com/article 164163.html
- 5. Comparative Effects of Telmisartan versus Valsartan on HOMA-IR in type2 Diabetes Mellitus Patients with Hypertension. (*Indian Journal of Applied Research Volume:* 04, Issue: 1, Jan 2014).
 - **Journal URL:** https://www.worldwidejournals.com/indian-journal-of-applied-research- (IJAR)/article/comparative-effects-of-telmisartan-versus-valsartan-on-homaandndash-ir-intype-2-diabetes-mellitus-patients-with-hypertension/MzA0OA==/?is=1
- 6. Comparative Effects of Telmisartan versus Valsartan on serum Leptin level, in hypertensive type2 Diabetes Mellitus patients. (*Iraqi journal of pharmacy Volume:* 14, No.1, 2014).
 - Journal URL: https://www.iasj.net/iasj?func=article&ald=173840
- 7. Effects of Glibenclamide vs Metformin on serum uric acid levels in patients with type-2 diabetes mellitus. (*Iraqi journal of pharmacy Volume: 11, No.1, 2011*).

 Journal URL: https://www.iasj.net/iasj?func=article&ald=49595

8. Human Recombinant Erythropoietin in the Treatment of Anemia of Patients with Chronic Renal Failure. (MJBU, Volume: 27, No.1, 2009).

Journal URL: https://mjbu.uobasrah.edu.iq/article/49013.html

Accepted Researches for Publication:

Submitted Researches for Publication:

9. Book Chapter: Pharmacology of Neuropeptides (Substance P, Vasoactive Intestinal Peptides (Vip), Neuropeptide Y, Calcitonin Peptides and Others) And Their Receptors.

The Researches Which Still in Performance Stages

- 10. Gynecological Problem and Vitamin D Deficiency.
- 11. The study of immunogenicity, stability and safety of Vaccine against Clostridium perfringens Alpha Toxins.